So the guy in front of us
is the real Madara.
（ナルト）じゃあ
目の前のアイツが　本物のマダラで→
Then the guy we thought
was Madara…isn't Madara?
今まで　マダラだと思ってたのは
別のヤツだったってことかよ？
（我愛羅）あぁ　そうなるな。
So it seems…
（テマリ）面の男が誰なのか　暁を
利用してきた　土影のアンタなら→
As Tsuchikage, you've utilized
the Akatsuki in the past.
Can you speculate who
that masked man might be?
推測することはできないのか？
There's no one I can think of.
（オオノキ）思い当たる人物は　おらん。
But it doesn't matter who he is!
We still need to stop him!
とにかく　敵が何者であれ→
止めねばならんことに
変わりない。
（マダラ）額当ては　忍か。
Their headbands say "Shinobi."
忍装束は　五大国それぞれだがな。
連合の新しい軍団か？
But I see them wearing shinobi gear
distinctly from each of
the Five Great Nations…
Is this a new allied army?
（無）これは　戦争のようなんでな。
It does appear that we're at war.
（マダラ）アイツのすることだ。
Coming from him...
何か　考えが
あってのことなんだろうが→
He must have something in mind.
But things don't seem like
they're going as planned.
あまり　計画どおりに
事が運んでいないようだな。
Why else would he revive me
in this state?
俺をこんな形で復活させるとは…。
この穢土転生の術者は誰だ？
Who is the caster of
the Reanimation Jutsu?
（無）さぁな。
Who knows?
（カブト）僕は　カブト。
I'm Kabuto.
（カブト）彼の協力者です。
I am…his collaborator.
穢土転生越しに語るとは
陰気なヤツだ。
Speaking through
a Reanimation Link?
Such a sneaky one you are…
（カブト）あなたの穢土転生は
特別製です。
Your Reanimation is quite special.
全盛期以上に仕上げておきました。
I've fixed you up so that you're even
greater than you were in your glory days.
お前…　俺の全盛期を
知っているというのか？
You know what I was like
during my "glory days"?
（カブト）いえ。
だから　ここで見せてください。
No.
Which is why
I want you to show me…
うちは伝説の力を…。
your legendary Uchiha power.
ただでは捕らえられんか。
I guess they won't be easy
to capture.
よかろう！
Very well…
Madara Uchiha
来るってばよ！
Here he comes!
Do not look directly into
his eyes!
（オオノキ）ヤツの目を
直接　見てはならんぞ！
うわ～！
《分裂した状態で
塵遁は使えんぞ》
You can't use the Particle Style in
your divided state right now…
Sensory Types! Watch Lord Mu!
感知タイプは　無様を見張れ！
（テマリ）待て！
Wait!
Gaara, you and Lord Tsuchikage
must recover first.
我愛羅と土影殿は回復が先だ。
ナルト！
分身はいいから　あのモードになれ。
Naruto! Instead of your clones,
go into that mode!
実は　もう　なれねえんだ。
The truth is, I can't anymore.
I used up my chakra
in the earlier fight!
さっきので
チャクラを使っちまってる。
うぅ…　うわっ！
（２人）ぐわ～っ！
Do you want to dance too?
お前も舞うか？
なめんな！
Don't underestimate me!
チッ…。
《火遁　豪火滅却！》
Fire Style!
Majestic Destroyer Flame!
術の範囲が広いぞ！
His jutsu spans a wide area!
《水遁　水陣壁！》
– Water Style! Wall of Water!
くるぞ！
Here he comes!
This is…as far as you'll go!
ここで　止める！
Massive Rasengan!
《超大玉螺旋丸！》
Earth Style: Mobile Core!
《土遁　地動核！》
うわ～っ！
A Susano'o…
須佐能乎か…。
すでに　万華鏡写輪眼になっとる。
He's already activated
the Mangekyo Sharingan!
まだか　ナルト。
How much longer, Naruto?!
もうちょいだってばよ。
Just hold on!
フン。
Sorry!
すまねえ。　やっとできたぜ。
I'm ready!
みんな　離れてくれ！
Get back, everyone!
いけ　風影。
Go, Kazekage!
土遁　軽重岩の術！
Earth Style:
Lightened Boulder Jutsu!
辺りの砂も軽くしといたからの。
I made the surrounding
sand lighter too!
《ここまで砂が軽く…
これなら！》
With sand this light,
I could…!
ナルト！
あぁ　行くぞ！
Naruto!
Yeah! Let's go!
《我愛羅：サスケのと同じなら
外部からの攻撃は効かない。
If it's like Sasuke's,
external attacks are ineffective.
ならば　マダラの足元にある
砂を使えばいい》
So I should use the sand
at Madara's feet!
行け！　ナルト！！
Go!
Naruto!
はぁ～　螺旋手裏剣！
Rasen Shuriken!
（シカク）面の男は　なぜ己を→
Why did the masked man
specifically claim to be Madara?
わざわざマダラと
名乗ったのでしょうか？
（綱手）マダラという存在が　この世に
生きているのではないか？
The presence of Madara...
（綱手）欺まんに満ちた存在でも
そう思わせておけば→
Even if he were a fraud,
if you can convince the world of,
his existence, it would tremble in fear.
世界は恐怖する。
その名が力なんだ。
The name itself is power.
その名は注意を引きつけ
みんなを戦争に巻き込むだけの→
That name made us
throw caution to the wind…
It fooled us,
then drew us all into war!
無視できないハッタリになった。
（綱手）私たちは　もう
釣られちまったのさ。
We've been had all along.
多すぎるな。
Too much energy…
す…　吸い取りやがった。
H-He…absorbed it!
これってば…　なんで？
What the…?! How?
なんでコイツが
輪廻眼になんだってばよ。
How come he's got the Rinnegan?
（カブト）やはり　憶測どおり
写輪眼のいき着く先は→
My guess was right.
What comes naturally after
the Sharingan, is the Rinnegan.
輪廻眼でしたか。
俺がこの眼を開眼したのは
死の少し前だ。
I awakened the Rinnegan
just prior to my death.
カブトとか言ったな。
You said your name was Kabuto?
この体に何をした？
What did you do to this body?
（カブト）だから言ったでしょう。
Like I told you.
全盛期以上に仕上げておいたと。
I made you better than
you were at your peak.
キサマ　俺の体の秘密を…。
You bastard…
You know the secrets of my body?
あの　うちはの石碑を
読めもしないお前ごときが→
You can't even read
the Uchiha Stone Tablet!
解読したというのか？
But you still managed
to decipher it?
大蛇丸様と
僕の長年の実験データを元に→
I just tested some hypotheses
drawn from years of data
仮説を立ててみたまでです。
from experiments Lord Orochimaru
and I conducted.
そして今は　あなたが
その仮説を証明してくれる。
And now…
You are verifying my hypotheses.
六道仙人　あの神の力の一端に
触れることができる。
You are able to achieve
a piece of that God's…
the power of the Sage of Six Paths.
僕のつくったあなたの力で。
Thanks to the power I built into you.
勘違いするな。
お前のつくった力ではない。
Do not misunderstand.
This is not power of your creation!
ハハッ　くそっ…。
Damn!
ウ…　ウソだろ。
N-No way…
なんだよ　これ？
What is that?
じ…　次元が違う。
It's out of our league!
神の力か？
Is this the power of a god?
隕石…　どうやって？
A meteorite? How did he…?
これが　忍術だとでもいうのか？
Is that really ninjutsu?
逃げきれねえぞ　これ…。
We can't outrun it!
This is not good…
Damn it!
まだ諦めの言葉を口にするな！
It's still too early to give up!
何もせんうちから己を捨てるな！
Never give up without even trying!
少しでも
やれることをするんじゃ！
Do what you can, no matter how small
the effect it may have!
土影様！
Lord Tsuchikage!
皆　できるかぎり
ここから離れろ！
Everyone, get as far away
from here as possible!
Hey!
Run!
逃げろ～！
うわぁ～！
Hurry!
（カブト）僕たちごと？
You're taking us out too?
当たり前だ。
Of course.
穢土転生の術は　本来こうやって
道連れに使うものだ。
That was the original point
of the Reanimation Jutsu…
To take others out with you.
俺たちは少しして元に戻る。
We'll be restored shortly.
（マダラ）空を飛ぶ忍？
A shinobi that can fly…?
なら　あれは岩の両天秤の小僧か。
Then, is he that Fence Sitter brat
from the Stone?
土影のじいちゃん
何しようってんだ！？
What's Gramps Tsuchikage
trying to do?!
あの隕石を軽くして止める気だ！
He's going to try to lighten
the meteorite to stop it!
（オオノキ）うお～！
土遁　超軽重岩の術！
Earth Style: Lightened Boulder Jutsu!
うおっ…　うぅ！
うお～！！
《もう少し…　もう少しで
止められる！》
Just a tad more…
A little more…to stop it!
ぬおっ　うお～！！
両天秤の小僧め
少しはやるようになったな。
That Fence Sitter brat…
He's gotten a little better.
よし！
止まった！
All right!
It's stopped!
We're saved…
Leave it to Lord Tsuchikage.
はぁ…。
よかった。
I thought we were goners.
Well then…
さて　２個目はどうする　オオノキ。
What will you do about
the second one, Ohnoki?
おっ！？
何だ！？
What was that?!
（シカク）うおっ！　何があった！？
What happened?!
（いのいち）中継の情報部からだ。
This is from our Relay Intel Unit.
第４部隊の戦場に
空を覆うほどの大岩が→
A giant boulder big enough
to block out the sky
has been dropped onto
the Fourth Company's battlefield.
落とされたという情報あり。
この揺れは　その影響だ！
It's the source of this tremor!
第４部隊から
その後の情報はないのか！？
Any further reports from
the Fourth Company since then?
（青）なんということだ。
一度に　これだけの人数を…。
What's going on?
So many casualties…
in just one sweep!
間違いない。　マダラの術か何かだ。
I'm sure of it…
It's Madara's jutsu or
something close to it!
綱手様　このままでは…。
Lady Tsunade! At this rate…!
私が行く！
I'll go!
なんだよ…　これは…。
What in the world…
was that?!
くっ…。
ゴムのおっちゃん…
なんで　分身の俺なんかを…。
Rubber Pops…
I'm just a clone, so why did you…?!
他には悪いが　分身でも
お前の力を欠くわけにはいかん。
I feel bad about the others.
But clone or not, you are needed here.
勝つためだ。
In order for us to win.
土影のじいちゃんは！？
What about Gramps Tsuchikage?!
土影のじいちゃん！！
Gramps Tsuchikage!
大丈夫だ。　生きておられる。
It's okay.
He's alive…
ただし…　重傷だ。
But he's seriously hurt!
（カブト）これが六道仙人の力…。
So this is the power of
the Sage of Six Paths…
すばらしい。
フッ。
Magnificent!
懐かしい風景だ。
This landscape brings back memories.
カブトとかいったな。
お前は　どこまで知っている？
It's Kabuto, right?
How much do you really know?
俺のことを。
About me?
恐らくですが
初代火影　柱間と戦った→
I venture to guess…
In that battle against
the First Hokage Hashirama,
あの終末の谷で
あなたは死んでなどいなかった。
you did not die at Final Valley.
その時点では。
On that day…
あの戦いで
初代柱間に負けたものの→
though you lost to
the First Hokage Hashirama,
あなたは
柱間の力の一部を手に入れた。
you gained a portion of
his power in return.
違いますか？
Am I wrong?
だからか…　段取りのいいヤツだ。
No wonder…
You're well prepared.
俺たちの計画も知っているのか？
You know about our plan?
あまり詳しくは…
ただ僕は　あなたの味方です。
Not in detail…
But I am your ally.
あの偽マダラが計画どおり→
事を運ぶ気があるのかどうかは
わかりませんが…。
ところで　まだ生き残りが
ちらほらいますね。
土影と風影は　さすがにしぶとい。
どうしますか？
少し確かめておきたいことがある。
口寄せの術！
《くっ…　くっ…　腹が…　熱い…》
（九尾）わしを呼ぶ　このチャクラ…。
マダラか？
九尾は　まだ
捕らえられてないようだな。
そのための戦争ですよ？　これ。
九尾は人柱力の中にいます。
今はね　ほら。
ちょうど　あそこ。
あの少年が　九尾の人柱力
うずまきナルト君ですよ。
うずまき？
ミトの一族か。　さっき
俺を攻撃したガキじゃないか。
ですが　なかなかのヤツでしてね。
捕らえるのは　いいんですが
目の前のヤツは分身です。
さっさと
本体を取りにいきますか？
いや　試したい術がある。
何もないところでやるよりは
人がいたほうが絵になるだろう。
ヤツらだ！　４時の方向！
木遁　樹界降誕！
木遁まで…。
どうやら　ここまでのようだ…。
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで　ごゆっくり→
お楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！にっぽんの歌』。
今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手
１１組の皆さんによる→